I've got a question for you.
Shall and shall.
About girls.
Do you prefer when their
hair is down and flowing free?
Or do you think it's nicer
when they tie it back?
Come on, don't ignore me.
Just say something.
Anything. You're a pain. What?
I said to say anything.
But I didn't mean anything.
You have
to give me a serious answer.
It was a ridiculous
question and I refuse
to glorify it with an answer.
Hey, look up there.
It's Lewiston at last.
It's been so long.
A whole year. Now there is the
exhibition, then the Duke's castle.
I sent off mamma's
spirit on Paul Soldi.
What's wrong, Scarecrow? You look like
you have a fever. What?
No. I'm fine. He's still
calling me Scarecrow, as usual.
I guess he's
a little nicer these days.
Oh well, for now, the fact
that he's by my side is enough.
Hey, watch where you're leading
your horse. Are you crazy?
you not to refer to me that way.
Or don't you remember? You bird
brained fool? Um. I'm sorry.
Shameful. I haven't seen
you in a full year.
And yet this is how you
greet me? Long time no see.
Lewiston gets cold in the fall.
I thought
cats tried to stay out of cold
weather.
Preparing to hibernate. Mr. Cat.
What? Why, you. No, no, I'm sure
you didn't come
to Lewiston just to argue
with Shel.
What are you doing here?
Why would you ask that?
This here is different.
If I skip this, I couldn't do
business next year, could I?
Huh?
Seriously? Are you not aware?
Not aware of what?
Are those insufferable tightwads? I shouldn't even
be surprised at this point.
Let's go talk at my usual place.
Ah, it's been a while. I didn't
know you all were acquainted.
Believe it or not,
I'm friendly sometimes.
So, miss,
what have you been doing
this past year?
Is your work going well?
Yes. We spent the winter
here in Lewiston.
Then we traveled to some little towns
and villages selling sugar confections.
It sounds like you've been busy.
Then,
have you come back
to enter the exhibition?
Yes. Time really does fly. Proprietress.
Be right. There. Wow.
You traveled a lot this year,
and you must have seen
the sugar apple
trees along the way.
Did you notice anything odd? Mm.
Actually, yes.
On every tree we saw,
the flowers had set
poorly for some reason.
That probably means the harvest will
be lighter this time, right?
That's right.
The crop is awful this year.
Unbelievably awful. Normally everyone's free to
harvest as they please,
but this time scarcity
would probably cause conflicts.
So, hoping to circumvent that,
the dimwitted
reprobate came up
with an answer.
Reprobate Hugh Mercury, the
silver sugar viscount, remember?
Oh, right. Silly me.
So what did he say this year?
Individuals can't harvest
their own sugar apples.
And the same policy goes
for refining them, too.
So we're not allowed.
Instead, all the sugar
apples in the kingdom
will be harvested
in the name of the silver sugar
viscount,
and then they'll be refined.
Only sugar artisans
who help with the
refining will be given
silver sugar.
They'll receive an amount that's reflective of
how much work they did.
So if we need some silver sugar,
can't we just ask Hugh
if he can spare some?
I'm afraid it isn't that simple.
He did make the decree.
But the one
who holds the monopoly here.
Is the Radcliffe School.
I'll explain. You see,
there are Radcliffe
workshops all over the kingdom.
Each one's already gathered. All
the sugar apples in their area.
Artisans from the Page
and Mercury schools
are meeting up in their workshops to
help with the refining process,
and there's no other way
to obtain silver sugar.
I think I understand, but I
haven't heard anything about it.
Well, you should have.
According to that,
reprobates orders, Radcliffe should have
spread the news around.
And they were supposed
to make it known
to all artisans,
even to wanderers like us.
They chose not to tell us.
They're relentless.
They're constantly harassing
her, telling her to get
out of town. It never ends. Ah.
Which is why I said they were
petty tightwads earlier.
I've heard the talk. You're the
famous sugar artisan Anne Halford,
who crafted that piece
for Duke Ahlborn.
Of course they're
jealous of you. And now
they're trying to punish
you for your success.
Then tell me something.
If I wanted
to enter the exhibition
for this year,
what would I need to do?
Exactly.
You're supposed to use silver sugar
that you refined for yourself,
or they won't let you compete.
So what do they expect
everyone to do?
They didn't tell you
that part either. Of course,
if you want to take
part in the exhibition,
then for a brief period of time
you will stay
at the Radcliffe Workshop.
They'll supply you
with some sugar apples,
which you can refine for your pieces
under their supervision, of course.
That being said,
you do have to assist
in the greater refining
process as well.
There's no time.
True, you'll only get
to do your
personal work at night,
so everyone who was
planning to compete
began their stay at the workshop
over two weeks ago.
This was going to be the year
that I became
a silver sugar master,
so I could make a sugar
confection worthy of the festivities.
No, I refuse to let something
like this get in my way.
All right,
then it would appear I need
to go visit
the Radcliffe workshop.
What do you two think?
Will you join me?
Of course I will. I did say
to the depths of the underworld,
didn't I?
I'll go too. After all, you're a
fool.
You shouldn't be left alone.
Sounds like it's all settled.
I'll guide you there.
But nothing more.
If you're a true artisan,
then you'll have to overcome
this challenge on your own.
Right. I suppose we'll let
you lead us for now. Mister Cat.
I told you,
stop calling me Mister Cat.
Everything within these walls belongs
to the Radcliffe workshop.
That's amazing.
All right. If you could
just sign this on
that desk over there.
Hey, I'd like to help as well.
Oh, of course. Let's see.
Your name is an R.
Just great. Do you know him?
We have a history.
Hey, Jonas. It's rude
to keep people waiting.
Please excuse him. I'm Sammy Jones, and
I'm in charge of reception.
You're the famed silver
sugar master, Alf Hingley.
I believe I'm quite familiar.
All we
need is your
signature right here,
and then I'll show
you to your room.
Oh, don't mind me.
The person standing
behind me is the one
you'll be dealing
with. And what do you want?
I'm here to help out with
a refining of the silver sugar.
You see, sir, I am entering the
sugar confectionery exhibition.
What? You a girl? All right.
I know the type.
You just call yourself
an artisan. But you
can't make a decent
confection to save your life.
Our workshop is for real craftsmen,
not for silly little girls.
But I am a real sugar artisan.
In fact,
I have a formal endorsement.
And who's it from? Your mom?
The former Duke of Felix.
So you're the infamous
Anne Halford. I see,
you're the one who set Jonas
up at the competition last year.
Rumor has it you seduced
the silver sugar Viscount.
You must have done
sordid things to gain
favor from the Duke
of Felix as well.
How dare.
You? Regardless of who you are,
you won't be granted access.
Why not?
And you've a companion fairy.
We have
a strict policy
that only labor fairies
and those involved in the refinement
process are allowed to stay.
So we won't
even consider letting you
in until you go
and sell that thing.
How's not a companion fairy?
It's the rule.
Now get out of here. Clean yourself
up before you try again.
Sammy, that's enough of your
rudeness. Oh, Keith, I was just.
You're tarnishing the name
of the Radcliffe workshop.
So I suggest you be
quiet before I get upset.
Who are you?
My associate was terribly rude.
Forgive him.
Keith Powell.
I'm a sugar artisan. Greetings.
Ah. Ah. It's nice to meet you.
I'm in Helford.
Hey there. Powell.
I didn't know you did
business with the Radcliffe School, Mr.
Hingley. What a treat.
Look, Keith, this young lady
has a companion ferry with her.
We can't allow them
inside the rules. Say, I told.
You he's not a companion.
He's a warrior type.
My goodness, how striking. I've
never seen one this beautiful.
Say, Anne,
I don't suppose there's any
chance you'd want
to relinquish him?
Oh, no.
She doesn't belong to me.
He's my friend.
He just stays by my side
because it makes me so happy.
If that's the case,
there is a way
you two can enter
the workshop together. Oh.
This year I'm competing in the
sugar confectionery exhibition.
And to make my piece,
I'll need a model.
Model, so. I will have
to borrow him occasionally.
That qualifies him to stay.
If you approve.
Borrow him. He's not a possession. That's
fine. Show us the papers.
But, shell. It's just
a trivial inconvenience.
You want me with you?
Huh?
We'll do it.
Now this building is where
the artisans stay.
Most of them sleep
in the same room.
Silver sugar masters
or those who have
the equivalent skill get private rooms based
on the school master's discretion.
And this room is just for you.
Wait, I get a private room.
We wouldn't
expect a young lady to share
her quarters with everyone else.
Then this is where I stay. Let
me know if you need anything
more. What is this? Great.
Ha ha ha! Ha ha ha ha!
What's wrong?
Keith has a private
room as well,
so his skills
must be worthy of it.
Unlike that braggart Jonas,
he's so arrogant.
And Keith seems to know
Cat from some other place.
I wonder who he could be.
Oh, dear. You remind me
of a squirrel? Really?
That's a lot
cuter than a scarecrow.
You're frantic.
Just like a squirrel that's
darting around in search
of its food.
I should have known that was it.
Let's see when I look more
grown up. If my hair was down,
which way would shall
think was prettier?
I'm trying to break
the mirror with your mind.
No, I was checking on my hair,
that's all. Is it all right?
It's the same as always.
No issues.
Um. Shall. Do you think it
looks better for hair to be.
Be what? Huh? Never mind. It's
not important. I have to go.
I'm asking the same
questions as Mr. Lid Pod.
It's time to start working
as hard as I can. All right.
Anne. Good morning. Hello there.
Keith.
Are you starting your work now?
Oh, no. I'm off today.
Every seven days,
one of us gets a day off.
So I was hoping you might let
me borrow shell.
Look, Keith,
I told you, Shell's not
an object I can lend out.
Oh, right.
You made it clear that he was
a treasured friend of yours.
I chose my words poorly.
It's fine. Oh, I wanted to thank
you for yesterday.
You really saved me.
Though I don't understand
why you're being so kind to me.
You're an artisan who's been recognized by
the Duke of Felix himself.
I have no reason to treat
you poorly. Also.
But I get the sense
you and I are similar.
What do you mean?
Well, your mother's
name was Emma Helford, correct?
You've heard of her?
Yes. In fact,
I met Madam Halford
when I was only about
4 or 5 years old.
I was surprised
to find out there
was a woman.
Silver sugar master.
You meant mama.
You see,
I'm the son of Edward Powell.
Silver sugar master.
Just like your mother.
Wait a minute. Edward Powell.
Right. Previous Viscount?
Indeed.
Thanks to him, I met a lot
of silver sugar masters,
including Alf Hingley.
My mother told me
he was a wonderful
silver sugar viscount who
served for over 20 years.
And if I recall, about six
months before mama passed away.
Sickness took him.
He may well have been wonderful,
but I wouldn't have known that back
when my father was Viscount.
There was a year like this where
the sugar apple
harvest was lacking.
Apparently there was
a great deal of chaos.
My father always
regretted that year.
I believe your father came from the
page school. Isn't that right?
So why are you
with the Radcliffe School?
Because if I'd enrolled with Paige, they'd
have given me special treatment.
Since I'm Paul's son.
I hated that idea.
So I came here where I'd be
just like any other artisan.
That's what I thought, at least.
But it's not all that different.
I respected my father,
but my situation
was terribly restrictive
and I couldn't participate
in the exhibition as long
as he was alive.
Why not? Because if
I had received the Royal Medal,
the critics would have
spread gossip about me.
They'd say the Royal
family favored me because
I was the son
of the silver sugar viscount.
And if I hadn't won, they'd have
judged me for failing in
spite of who my father was.
I couldn't risk his reputation.
But the mourning period is over,
which means as of this year,
I should be
able to compete
in the exhibition.
Are. Anyway,
I thought I'd work on my piece
for a bit today.
This shall. In your room?
Um, yes. If you ask him, then
I'm sure he'll be glad to help
you. Excellent.
Well, then, good luck.
Keith isn't letting his circumstances hold him
back from doing his best.
So I can't either.
I won't let him beat me.
I'm sorry for the early hour.
I did make
a promise, so I'll keep it.
Shall I do a trick?
Take off my clothes,
perhaps.
Give your orders, boy. Quickly.
Boy. All right. It appears we're
about the same age, though.
Could you go stand
by that window? There.
That should be great.
I want to get
a good sense of your
air and appearance.
It's too bad for Anne.
She just got here,
and the rest of us already
refined all the sugar we need.
I hope she
prepared ahead of time.
Not at all.
In fact, your schoolmates
neglected to tell her what
happened this year. Lucky you.
They didn't tell her.
Selfish cowards. The
lot of them.
It's downright disgraceful.
That upsets me.
But I'm glad that
Ann is entering
the exhibition anyway.
If it were only
the artisans from here,
I wouldn't have
any competition to speak of.
Rumor has it the royal medal's
going to Sammy this time.
But if you ask me,
he isn't even worth a mention.
Jonas is capable enough, but his work
is missing a crucial element.
I've been waiting for an
opponent with equal skill,
so she's going to make
it worthwhile for me.
Also.
This is probably the only time
I'll get to compete against
Anne at the exhibition.
This year will be
Anne's final chance.
It is a great honour for me.
It's her final chance.
That's right. If she
can't become a silver
sugar master this time.
Then she can never become one.
Everyone's too jealous of her.
There was last year's contest.
Then all
that business involving
the former Duke of Phylax.
Even if this had been a normal
year when artisans could
harvest their own sugar apples,
they still would have hindered
her in some way.
I'd say this was
a stroke of good fortune,
because working with us will
guarantee her some silver sugar.
But it won't
happen again this way.
She'll never be able to get
the supplies she needs.
That said, you mustn't tell her.
I don't
want her to feel
that additional pressure.
I'd rather compete
with her fairly.